A Guide to the Papers of Howard W. Smith, 1933-1966
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series XV: Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook, (1956) 1966, 11
    clippings re: Smith's primary fight with George C. Rawlings, Jr., and Smith's loss. 82 pages, black leatherette cover.
  - Scrapbook, 1966, 12
    of clippings and photographs re: Smith's campaign in the Democratic primary against George C. Rawlings, Jr. and re: his loss and retirement. 34 pages, medium blue leatherette cover
  - a. Scrapbook, 1939-1940, 13
    of clippings (some original, but chiefly negative photostats) re: Smith's Special Congressional Committee investigation of the National Labor Relations Board. 1-29 ff., black cloth covers loose-leaf. Chronological summary and index on pp. i-v to this book and succeeding two.
  - b. Scrapbooks, 1940 January - March, 13
    of clippings (originals and photostats) of Smith and the special Congressional Committee investigating the N.L.R.B. 30-55 ff. black cloth covers loose-leaf. Summary and index in Vol. 1
  - c. Scrapbook, 1940 April - August, 13
    of clippings (some originals and some photostats) re: the special committee investigating the N.L.R.B. 56-82 pp. black cloth cover loose leaf. Tab index by months, indexed in Vol. 1
  - H.R. 2 loose-leaf binders, 1941-42, 14
    stamped "Verbatim Record of the Proceedings of the Special House Committee Investigating the National Labor Relations Board" but containing pages torn from the Congressional Record, 1942, treating Smith's speeches on floor of House. Also contained are some notes of legislation. 1 ca. 75 pages black pebble-grain leatherette cover; 2) ca. 150 pages cover as above
  - H.R. 2 copies of proposal, 1961, 15
    for a James Madison Memorial Building in Washington, execute by J. George Stewart, architect of the Capitol, together with a letter, 21 July 1961, covering the proposal from Stewart to Smith, and copies of resolutions re: the Memorial
  - Guestbook, 1961-1965, 16
    Of visitors to Smith's Congressional office, ca. 100 page red leatherette cover.
- Series XVI: Thomas Jefferson Memorial Architectural Competition Drawings
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Washington, D.C. Office of John Russell Pope, Architect March 29, 1938, 1; 4'6 1/2" x 2' 1/4"
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Tidal Basin Site, Washington, D.C. Office of John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme "G" February 16, 1938, 2; 41 1/2" x 2 1/4'
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Washington, D.C. Eggers & Higgins Architects March 16, 1938, 3; 5 1/6' x 2 1/4'
  - Map of Washington, D.C. Showing possible sites A-B-C and D for the Thomas Jefferson Memorial, 4; 3'8" x 1'10"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson Mall Site opposite Archives, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, 5; 3'5" x 1' 11"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Mall Site opposite Archives, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, General Plan B, 6; 3'3" x 1'8"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Lincoln Park Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, City Plan C, 7; 4'3" x 1'7"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Mall Site opposite Archives, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, 8; 4'10" x 2'9 1/2"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Lincoln Park Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, General Plan C, 9; 3'2" x 2'1"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Mall Site opposite Archives, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect Detail Plan B, 10; 2'9 1/2" x 2'7"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Lincoln Park Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, Detail Plan C, 11; 3'11" x 2'5"
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme "B", 12; 3'7" x 2'6"
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme "B", 13; 3'7" x 2'6"
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Section on North-South Axis, Washington, D.C., Scheme B, John Russell Pope, Architect, 14; 3'7" x 2'6"
  - Diagramatic Elevation of Scheme "B" taken at angle of 45º to main axis, Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, 15; 3'6" x 2'
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme B, 16; 5'10" x 2'9"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Tidal Basin Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, General Plan A, 17; 3'1'2' x 2'1"
    [First Tidal Basin Scheme A (Pantheon), small general plan]
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Tidal Basin Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, Elevation D/A, 18; 3'10" x 1'11"
    [First Tidal Basin Scheme A (Pantheon), front elevation]
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Tidal Basin Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, Section D/A, 19; 3'5" x 2'1"
    [First Tidal Basin Scheme A (Pantheon), section (section applies also to Scheme B)]
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Tidal Basin Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, Detail Plan D/A, 20; 4' x 3'3"
    [First Tidal Basin Scheme A (Pantheon) plan]
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Tidal Basin Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, "A", 21; 4'10" x 2'9"
    [First Tidal Basin Scheme A (Pantheon) Perspective]
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Anacostia Park Site, Washington, D.C., End of East Capitol Street, John Russell Pope, Architect, "D", 22; 4'10" x 2'9"
    [Scheme D (Anacostia Park Site) Perspective]
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Anacostia Park Site, End of East Capitol Street, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, City Plan D, 23; 4'3" x 1'7"
    [Scheme D (Anacostia Park Site) Plan]
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Anacostia Park Site, Washington, D.C., End of East Capitol Street, John Russell Pope, Architect, General Plan D, 24; 2'4" x 1'7"
    [Scheme D (Anacostia Park Site) General Plan]
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme A, 25; 5'9" 1/2" x 2'9"
    [Scheme A (Pantheon Scheme in Tidal Basin) Perspective]
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme A, Section on North-South Axis, 26; 3'7" x 2'6"
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme A, 27; 3'7" x 2'6"
    [Scheme A (Pantheon Scheme in Tidal Basin) Plan]
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Scheme A, 28; 3'7" x 2'6"
    [Scheme A (Pantheon Scheme in Tidal Basin) Front Elevation]
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., General Plan, John Russell Pope, Architect, 29; 3'7" x 2'6"
    [Scheme A (Pantheon Scheme in Tidal Basin) General Plan]
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Plan showing estimates A, B, and C., 30; 3'7" x 2'6"
    [Scheme A (Pantheon Scheme in Tidal Basin) Plan showing areas covered by various estimates]
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Diagramatic elevation of Scheme A taken at angle of 45º to main axis, 31; 3'6" x 2'
    [Scheme A (Pantheon Scheme in Tidal Basin) elevation at 45º angle to main axis]
  - The Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, Diagramatic Elevation of Scheme A, View from South, 32; 3'4" x 2'
    [Scheme A (Pantheon Scheme in Tidal Basin), South elevation
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Lincoln Park Site, Washington, D.C. John Russell Pope, Architect, Elevation C, 33; 2'9" x 1'11"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Washington, D.C., Office of John Russell Pope, Architect, March 29, 1938 (Aerial View), 34; 2'7" x 2'3"
  - A Memorial to Thomas Jefferson, Washington, D.C., John Russell Pope, Architect, March 29, 1938, 35; 2'7" x 2'3"
  - Schemes E, F, and G, Diagramatic Plan showing extent of estimates A and B, 36; 2'11" x 1'1 1/2"
  - The Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., Scheme F, November 20, 1937, 36; 2'10 1/2" x 1'7"
    [Scheme F (Circular Open Colonnade) Elevation]
  - The Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., Scheme E, July 21, 1937, 36; 2'11 1/2" x 1'6 1/2"
  - Lincoln Memorial, December 11, 1936, 36; 3'2" x 1'6 1/2"
    drawn at a scale of 20 feet equal 1 inch for comparison with elevations of proposed Thomas Jefferson Memorial drawn at the same scale
  - The Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., Side elevation, Scheme G, November 12, 1937, 37; 2'1 1/2" x 1'1/2"
    [Scheme G (circular open colonnade) side elevation
  - The Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., Scheme F, November 20, 1937, 37; 2'1" x 1'11 1/4"
    Plan [Scheme F (circular open colonnade) plan]
  - The Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., Scheme G, November 12, 1937, 37; 2'1" x 1'11 1/4"
    [Scheme G (circular open colonnade) general plan]
  - The Jefferson Memorial, Washington, D.C., Scheme E, July 21, 1937, 2'1" x 1'11 1/4", 37; 2'1" x 1'11"
    Plan Scheme E showing memorial site with slight change in contour of present Tidal Basin development of south axis of the mall for the Thomas Jefferson Memorial, John Russell Pope, Architect, July 21, 1937